

Java & Devops Immediate Joinee 4.9 years ,Skill set - Corejava, MicroservicesSpring core,Linux,Jenkins,DockerAnsible,JIRA,AWS,GIT, Kuberenetes ,Responsibilities-Development,Build ,Release Management of Continuous Integration,Application Deployment.



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 9 Month(s)

Current Company: Cerner Healthcare Solutions Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [INFORMATION

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad SCIENCE]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Core Java, Spring Core, GIT, Jenkins, Maven, Docker, Ansible, Kubernetes

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

IMMEDIATE JOINEE 4.9 yrsDEVOPS & JAVA Worked as Software Engineer in JAVA Development Using java, spring boot and microservices, Deployment, and Release applications from one environment to other environment tightly maintaining CI/CD using JENKINS, GIT, DOCKER, ANSIBLE AND KUBERNETES.

Work Experience

Cerner Healthcare Solutions as Senior Software Engineer Jun 2018 to Till Date

- * Develop front end screens using RCP ,Jface and CoreJava.
- * Created Jenkins CI/CD pipelines for continuous build & deployment and integrated SonarQube plugins in Jenkins for automated testing and for Code quality check.
- * Used MAVEN as build tools on Java projects for the development of build artifacts on the source code.
- * Involved in Merging the Branches in Github.
- * Experience in writing Ansible Playbook for few repetitive tasks.
- * Participated in the release cycle of the solution, which involves environments like Dev, QA, UAT and Production in Linux virtual box.
- * Experience in writing yaml file for creating Pods in Kubernetes.
- * Support and conduct sessions to different teams to spread knowledge on DevOps and configuration management.
- * Worked on AWS Services EC2,S3, IAM.

Cerner Healthcare Solutions as Software Engineer

Jun 2016 to Nov 2017

Worked as Software engineer and involved in development of RCP Applications ,Build Management,Release Management,Continuous Integration,Application Deployment,Requirement Gathering, Skillsets-Linux,Jenkins,Ansible,JIRA,AWS,GIT,Kuberenetes,Docker,Nagios,Maven

IBM as Software Engineer Jan 2016 to Sep 2016

The Global Provisioning System (GPS) is a client-server application that is part of AT&T.A variety of users who participate in the Inventory, Provisioning, and Procurement (IP&P) process use the Global Provisioning System

Responsibiltes

Involved in development of front-end RCP(Rich Client Platform) pages to business logic. Implementing Controller logics, DAO's (Data Access Objects) of assigned modules.

Involved in creating Audit Documents.

Involved in writing Unit testing and attending team agile meeting and scrum meeting.

Hawkinfomatics as Software Engineer

Apr 2014 to Aug 2015

To provide emergency air-rescue services for Subscribers of 'Aviators Air Ambulance' shall be entitled to the air medical services within the operations areas as provided by Aviators Air Ambulance for the period for which the member has enrolled for. Aviators shall provide air medical services in the form of helicopters/flights to the member

Responsibiltes

Interacting with Client.Involved in Integration of JSP pages to business logic.

Implementing Controller logics, Business logics, DAO's (Data Access Objects) of assigned modules.

Coding of HTML/JSP as per requirements.Contributed in preparing Documentation about the Product.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (INFORMATION SCIENCE) from Visveswaraiah Technological University (VTU) in 2012

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	t Used Experience	
Jenkins		2020	1 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
GIT		2020	1 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
Ansible		2020	1 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
Kubernetes		2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
spring boot			2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
AWS		2020	1 Year(s) 4 Month(s)	
MAVEN		2020	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
CORE JAVA	1.8	2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
DOCKER		2020	2 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
MICROSE		0	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Kannada	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: External Consultant

Client: Sarvamoola

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2020 - Till Date

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Worked as external consultant in building the working environment using devops related tools like AWS,git

Project Title: Revenue cycle Client: Cerner Healthcare Solutions Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Nov 2018 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role Description: Worked as Software engineer Project Details: Cerner Healthcare Solutions, Bangalore

Cerner Corporation is a pioneer in providing Software Solutions in Healthcare industry. It has its major foot print in US,

Canada and Middle East.

Responsibiltes

Develop front end screens using RCP ,Jface and CoreJava.

Involved in Dockerization of the Project.

Involved in the Development of the Projects like Building and deploying using Jenkins. Involved in Merging the Branches in Github.

Worked on the configuration management tool Ansible for deploying the codes across different platforms.

Worked on various field like gathering requirements and interacting with clients etc.

Participated in the release cycle of the product, which involves environments like Dev, QA, UAT and Production. Support and conduct sessions to different teams to spread knowledge on DevOps and configuration management.

Project Title: WEB APPLICATION

Client: Air Rescue

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Oct 2014 - Aug 2015 Project Location: BANGALORE Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Role: Programmer Team Size: 7

Skill Used: CORE JAVA, J2Ee, SQL Server, Hibernate, Spring, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Javascript,

Role Description: * Involved in Project Plan and Estimation.

Interacting with Client.

- Involved in Integration of JSP pages to business logic.
- Implementing Controller logics, Business logics, DAO's (Data Access Objects) of assigned modules.

Project Details: To provide emergency air-rescue services Subscribers of Aviators Air Ambulance shall be entitled to the air medical services within the operations areas as provided by Aviators Air Ambulance for the period for which the member has enrolled for. Aviators shall provide air medical services in the form of helicopters/flights to the member and other persons covered under the membership clauses agreed to in the subscription form. The only cost will be the subscription charges one pays for the fixed term. Subscription ensures that the subscriber will have no out-of-pocket expenses for being flown to the nearest appropriate medical facility deemed as necessary by Aviators (Services).

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time